Mss.Ms.Coll.97
American Philosophical Society
Frank Siebert Papers
1929-1998
Mss.Ms.Coll.97
American Philosophical Society
56.0 Linear feet
56 linear feet.
Frank Siebert (1913-1998) is one of the key contributors to the field of Algonquian linguistics. While he did not pursue a degree in linguistics or anthropology, he independently acquired the skills and knowledge of a professional scholar. His work on Penobscot is some of the best and most comprehensive in existence. The Siebert Collection documents the interest and work of Frank Siebert in the linguistics of the Algonquian family of languages, particularly Penobscot. The collection includes correspondence, research notes, drafts and published manuscripts by Siebert, as well as secondary sources consulted by Siebert. To a lesser extent, it contains material that documents Siebert’s personal life, his interest in book collecting and his career as a physician.
Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998
Box 1-112
Scope and Contents note
The Siebert Collection documents the interest and work of Frank Siebert in the linguistics of the Algonquian family of languages, particularly Penobscot. The collection includes correspondence, research notes, drafts and published manuscripts by Siebert, as well as secondary sources consulted by Siebert. To a lesser extent, it contains material that documents Siebert’s personal life, his interest in book collecting and his career as a physician. Siebert carried on frequent and long standing correspondence with others in the field of American Indian linguistics. In their letters, Siebert and his colleagues presented and discussed linguistic theories and evidence and kept each other notified about their current projects. Often these letters included articles of interest or drafts of papers with a request for comments.
Siebert’s research, and thus his field notes, center on the Penobscot language. The field notes also display an interest in related topics, such as Indian history and anthropology, Maine geography and natural history. His two major projects on Penobscot, the Penobscot Dictionary and Penobscot Texts, demonstrate Siebert’s desire not only to understand the linguistic operation of the language, but to preserve the language itself as well as the culture and history of the Penobscot people. Siebert made several sound recordings of Penobscot songs, stories and speech to this end. While Algonquian languages were Siebert’s main interest, he did a significant amount of research on Catawba, a Siouan language. He kept extensive field notes on Catawba from which he produced a published article.
Siebert’s field research was augmented by a study of secondary sources. He consulted many journals, articles and manuscripts on the disciplines of linguistics and anthropology as well as on Algonquian and Catawba linguistics. Also included are documents particularly useful as sources for Siebert’s work on Indian history. A small portion of the collection represents Siebert’s interest in book collecting, his medical career and his personal life. He kept articles, newspaper clippings and notes on diseases and medical practice. In addition, he accumulated book advertisements, catalogues and auction notices. Siebert kept up personal correspondence with friends, whose letters he kept with those from his colleagues. He was also interested in politics and saved newspaper articles on current political and social issues.
Native American Images note: Nearly 800 ink and pencil sketches, photographs, newspaper clippings, and black and white photocopy images of Catawba and Penobscot tribes collected and drawn by Frank Siebert from 1932-1946 and 1985-1994. The ethnological sketches in notebooks reflect social life and customs, including tools, traps, design motifs, ball games, wampum and picture writing. Research notes contain photocopies from various sources. Many original and printed maps of North Carolina and Maine pinpointing tribal distributions.
Biographical/Historical note
Frank Siebert (1913-1998) is one of the key contributors to the field of Algonquian linguistics. While he did not pursue a degree in linguistics or anthropology, he independently acquired the skills and knowledge of a professional scholar. His work on Penobscot is some of the best and most comprehensive in existence.
Siebert began his Penobscot research in 1932 while an undergraduate studying chemistry at Haverford College. It was in this year that he made his first trip to Indian Island, Maine in the Penobscot Reservation. While a medical student at the University of Pennsylvania, Siebert continued to pursue his interest in anthropological linguistics. He received training in this field by attending lectures by Franz Boas and Edward Sapir. He associated with Frank Speck and the anthropologists and linguists who congregated in Speck’s office. Throughout his career as a pathologist, Siebert continued his Penobscot field work. He also had an interest in Catawba, which he did field research on in 1941, during a six month break from medical school. Later in life, he studied secondary sources on the language. After his retirement, Siebert dedicated all his time to his research. In 1968, he moved to Old Town, Maine so he could work more frequently with his informants.
When Siebert began his research, there were about one hundred fluent speakers of Penobscot. Over the years, Siebert worked with many informants. His longest collaboration was with Andrew Dana, with whom he worked closely for over thirty years. Over the course of Siebert’s life, most of the Penobscots fluent in their native language died. This left Siebert among, or possibly, the last speaker with any great knowledge of the language. He continued his work up to his death in 1998, leaving much of it unpublished.
Some of Siebert’s work built on existing studies of Algonquian languages. Siebert’s mentor, Frank Speck, had worked on both Penobscot and Catawba. Also, Siebert’s work on Proto-Algonquian began with a correction of Leonard Bloomfield’s reconstruction. However, as Siebert felt strongly that scholars should do their own research, all his writings have come from his own field work. This research formed the basis of some of the most important contributions to the field of Algonquian linguistics. His Penobscot Dictionary is the most complete documentation of the language in existence. Siebert also collected folklore and history of the Penobscot Indians, which he compiled in a volume called Penobscot Texts. While most of his work was linguistic, Siebert also wrote articles on Algonquian history. He combined these interests in his reconstruction of Proto-Algonquian and a study of eighteenth century Virginia Algonquian. He used a knowledge of natural history as well as linguistics and history to identify the original homeland of the Algonquians.
Siebert maintained a frequent correspondence with his mentors and colleagues, including C.F. Voegelin, Frank Speck, Edward Sapir, Ives Goddard, Gordon Day and Willard Walker. Through letters, they shared ideas and augmented each other’s work. Siebert was also an avid book collector, amassing a large and valuable collection of works on United States and American Indian history. In addition, he belonged to several historical and archeological societies. Siebert was awarded grants by the Guggenheim Foundation, the NSF and NEH to carry out his research.
Catawba Indians; Eastern Woodlands Indians; Gelatin silver prints; Indians of North America--Maine; Indians of North America--North Carolina; Newspaper clippings.; Penobscot Indians; Petroglyphs; Photocopies; Photographs--Color; Picture-writing; Sketches.; Southeast Indians
- I. Correspondence, 1929-1997; 3.5 Linear feet (Box 1-7)
  - Abbot, C. G. (Charles Greeley), 1936; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Smithsonian Institution
  - Abernathy, Charley (H. C.), Bulk, 1938-1944; 1938-1991; 21.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Adams, Randolph G., 1943; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    William L. Clements Library, University of Michigan
  - Aderhold, Kathryn, 1942; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    Mercy Hospital, Benton Harbor, Michigan
  - AFSC Maine Indian Program, 1987; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Aguilar, Gloria V., 1990; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    National Science Foundation
  - [Aimes, S.], 1934; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    British Museum. Receipt
  - Akers, Gerald, 1980-1989; 4.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Akins, A. X. (Andrew X.), 1984-1993; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    Sappier, James. Penobscot Language Program
  - American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1967; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - American Geographical Society, 1939; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - American Library Service, 1929; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Arbour, Keith, 1987-19993, n.d.; 22.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Archie, J. F., 1955; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    Dunton, George E.; Faulkner, Gretchen
  - Archives of the Moravian Church, 1995; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Armalavage, Leon (Army), 1939-1996; 30.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Atmore, Bob, 1939-1984, n.d.; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    Chadbourne, Hunt, Jaeckel, and Brown
  - Austin, R. S., 1940-1941; 4.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    University of Cincinnati College of Medicine
  - Ayres, James E., 1977; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Bahndorf, Bunnie and Bob, 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Balch, James, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Balfour, Donald C., 1939; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    University of Minnesota, Mayo Foundation
  - Bangor Daily News, 1982; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Barbour, P. L., 1962; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Barringer, George, 1972; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    Harrison, Henry, S. J.
  - Bates, Albert C., 1933; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    Connecticut Historical Society
  - Bates, Albert M., 1937; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    Shryock Radio Company
  - Baumann-Nelson, Eunice, 1994; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    Letter to Paul Chappin, National Science Foundation
  - Beaumont, Raymond M., 1990; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Becker, Ellen, 1990; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Becker, Herbert A., 1977; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    United States Department of Justice
  - Becker, Mary Druke, 1992; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    Newberry Library
  - Bennett, Charles J., 1934; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    British Museum
  - Berube, Al, 1973-1974; 4.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    Starbird, S. Glenn; Bureau of Indian Affairs
  - Bishop, Bailey, 1991; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Bishop, Robert R., 1988; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    Episcopal Academy
  - Bloch, Bernard, 1941; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    Linguistic Society of America
  - Blumer, Tom, 1996; 5.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Booker, Karen M., 1994; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    University of Kansas
  - Boots, Lalania, 1996; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Bourque, Bruce J., 1990-1991; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    Maine State Museum
  - Boyd, William, 1940; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Brejcha, Elmer, 1977-1989; 10.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - [Bromfield, Louis], 1944; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Brooks, Robert C., 1975-1976; 17.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Brooks, Seal T., 1940; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Brown, Cecil H., 1991; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    Enclosure missing
  - Brown, H. Tatnall, Jr., 1933-1939; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Brown, T. C., 1968-1969; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Buccini, Anthony F., 1996; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Buesing, Gregory, 1976; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    Wabanaki Treaties, 1775-1800
  - Bunting, John and Ruth, 1978-1994; 9.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Butterfield, Margaret, 1938; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    University of Rochester, Rush Rhees Library
  - Byers, Douglas S., 1940; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    Society for American Archaeology
  - Carroll-Horrocks, Beth, 1984; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    American Philosophical Society
  - Carrying Capacity Network, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    Miller, Monique A.
  - Castle, Laura, 1934; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Chamberlain, Martha, 1952-1965; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Chapin, Howard M., 1934; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    Rhode Island Historical Society
  - Chapin, Paul G., 1981; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Chase, George, 1986-1991; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    RESTRICTED
  - Chester, Roberta, 1989; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Cohen, William S., 1987; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    United States Senate
  - Colcord, Charles E., 1987; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Colick, Mary Catherine, 1948-1981; 6.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Columbia Museums of Art and Science, 2.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    Catawba Indian Pottery
  - Comfort, Howard, 1940-1944; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Comfort, W. W., 1933; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    Haverford College
  - Comments on Siebert's Suprasequential Phonemes, n.d.; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    Publisher's comments
  - Commonwealth of Pennsylvania. Bureau of Professional Licensing, 1934-1939; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
  - Conway, Jill K., 1992; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 1)
    American Antiquarian Society
  - Cook, Margaret G., 1989; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    Maine Archeological Society Bulletin
  - Cooper, John W., 1937; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    Catholic University of America
  - Corner, George W., 1965; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Costa, David J., 1997; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Cowan, J. M., 1941; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Cowan, William, 1974-1989; 9.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    Seeber, Pauleena
  - Cox, Edward W., 1933; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    Queen County Clerk's Office
  - [Crauly], Eunice, 1987-1994, n.d.; 4.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Crawford, James L., Jr., 1995; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Crawford, James M., 1972-1981; 2.0 folders (Box 2)
    - Folder 1, 1972-1976; 43.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    - Folder 2, 1976-1981; 9.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Crawford, William H., 1990; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Cruikshank, Clara C., 1984; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Curtis, George M., 1939; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    Ohio State University, Department of Research Surgery
  - D'Abate, Richard, 1994; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    Siebert/Garrett Native American Language Project. Letter to Paul Chapin
  - Dana, Andrew, 1937-1963; 13.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Danielson, Irvin, 1940-1941; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    University of Oklahoma, School of Medicine
  - Dann, John C., 1988; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    William Clements Library, University of Michigan
  - Davis, James J., 1939; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Davis, Kathy Siebert, 1995-1997; 5.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Dawson, Glen, 1959; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    Dawson's Book Shop
  - Day, Gordon M., 1966-1989; 7.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Dean, Nora Thompson, 1982; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    Touching Leaves Indian Crafts
  - DeBlois, A. D. (Albert D.), 1988; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    Penobscot Nation Algonquin Conference
  - DeMallie, Raymond J., 1979-1992; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    American Society for Ethnohistory
  - Denault, Raymond, 1963; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    Societe Canadienne du Microfilm
  - Dennee, JoAnne, 1990; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Denny, Peter, 1983-1993; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    University of Western Ontario
  - Dorrance, Frances, 1932-1936; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    Society for Pennsylvania Archaeology
  - Dorsey, H. W., 1929; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    Smithsonian Institution, Bureau of American Ethnology
  - Dorst, Stanley, 1941; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    University of Cincinnati, College of Medicine
  - Drapeau, Lynn, 1991; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    Universite du Quebec a Montreal
  - Drinkwater, Gertrude, 1967; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Dunn, Steve, 1996; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    Maine Public Television
  - Eastman Kodak Company, 1940; 6.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Eckstorm, Fannie H., 1936-1945; 10.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Erickson, Vincent O., 1989; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    Smith, Nicholas N. Regarding Peter Lewis Paul (1902-1989).
  - Erminie, 1936-1937; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Eugenics Publishing Company, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Ewing, Abigail, 1986-1987; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    Bangor Historical Society
  - Fenstermacher, R. H., 1940; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Ferm, William N., 1989-1990; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Finger Family -- Stephanie, Doug, Daniel, and Jonathan, 1996; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Fisher, Edwin R., 1957-1993; 4.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    Shadyside Hospital, Pittsburgh
  - Flaccus, Louis W., 1986-1987; 4.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Fogelson, Raymond D., 1979-1983; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    Includes excerpt from Gene Waddell, Indians of the South Carolina Low Country
  - Fonto, Minnie, 1940; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Fowler, William M., Jr., 1983; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    New England Quarterly
  - Francis, Paul, Jr., 1982; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Franzen, Louise, 1947; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Frazer, Elizabeth G., 1938; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Frazer, Grant, 1943-1988; 8.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Friedrich, Paul, 1987; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Fuller, Marion Cobb, 1941; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    Maine State Library
  - Gabriel, Newell, 1936-1938; 5.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Garnett, 1947; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Garrison, Curtis W., 1933; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    Library of Congress, Division of Manuscripts
  - Geary, James A., 1942; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Gedds, Donald P., 1933; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    Columbia University Press
  - Gehrt, Sarah B., 1991; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    University of Maine
  - Gerlach, R. F., 1932; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    Goodspeed's Book Shop
  - Giese, Paula, 1996; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Ginsberg, Michael, 1990; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
    Michael Ginsberg Books
  - Giroux, T., 1934-1935; 15.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - [Glireskey], Bill, 1990; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 2)
  - Goddard, Ives, 1966-1994, n.d.; 36.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Golla, Victor, 1985; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Gordon, David M., 1981-1992; 10.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Gordon, Ervin, 1941; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Gordon, Sallie, 1941-1945; 5.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Graf, J. E. (John Enos), 1941; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Grant, Anthony P., 1994; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
    Includes Anthony P. Grant, "On the Authorship of the Wea Primer (1837)."
  - Grant, Elihu, 1934; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Gravely, Benjamin F., 1932; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
    Benj. F. Gravely, Bookseller
  - Gray, Judith A., 1997; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
    Library of Congress
  - Greene, Evarts B., 1933; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Griffith, Mary, 1987; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Griscom, Ludlow, 1933; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
    Museum of Comparative Zoology
  - Guffey, Joseph F., 1938; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Haas, Mary, 1937-1986, n.d.; 37.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Haddleton, Alfred W., 1935; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Haile, Edward, 1976; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Haines, Lawrence E., 1937; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
    Wedding invitation
  - Halperin, Maurice, 1941; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
    Letter with enclosure, Oklahoma Federation for Constitutional Rights
  - Hamilton, Doris Harris, 1980-1995; 5.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Hamp, Eric, 1969-1989; 10.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Handbook of North American Indians, 1972-1974; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
    Sturtevant, William C.
  - Hardy, Charlotte W., 1947; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
    Eckstrom, Fannie H.
  - Hardy, Heather K. and Janine Scancarelli, 1993; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Harkort, Marie-Louise Liebe, 1985; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
    Mouton Publishers
  - Harper, Francis, 1963; 7.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - J. P. Harrington Conference, 1993; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Harrington, John P., 1940-1949; 7.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Harrington, M. R. (Mark Raymond), 1936; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
    Southwest Museum
  - Harris, W. L., n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
    Typed copy of letter written in 1896 to Western Georgia and Atlanta Railroad Company. Concerning a bull hit by a train.
  - Harris, Zellig, 1939; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Harrison, William Henry, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
    Handwritten copy of letter dated 6 November 1812, from Harrison to Governor R. J. Meigs.
  - Hayer, Altha, 1958; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Heckler, Helen, 1935; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
    Hrdlicka, Ales; Smithsonian Institution
  - Henderson, M. S., 1939; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Henigar, Gordon R., 1958-1959; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - [Herb], 1966; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
    Letter about model railroading.
  - Herkimer, C., Mrs., 1938; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
    Daughter of Nick Peters
  - Herzog, George, 1941; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Hess, Gertrude D., 1965-1970; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Hewson, A., [1937]; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
    Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, Department of Health, Anatomical Board
  - Hewson, John, 1970-1978; 14.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Hipple, Byron, 1985-1994; 4.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Hockett, Charles, 1964-1985; 4.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Houston, Annette, 1988; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
    Maine School Administration
  - Howe, Parkman D., 1955; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Hume, H. Alan, 1991-1992; 4.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Hummell, Judy, 1989; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Ila, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
    Chrsitmas card signed by Jack, Ila, Vic, Danny, and Ronnie
  - Indian Rights Association, 1960-1961; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
    American Indian Charter Convention
  - Indianapolis City Hospital, 1938; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
    Blank application form
  - International Journal of American Linguistics, 1980; 4.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
    Rood, David
  - Iron Thunderhorse, 1996; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - [J. S.], n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Jacobs, E. Atwood, 1938; 5.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
    Reading Hospital
  - Jameson, J. F. (John Franklin), 1933; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
    Letter to R. W. Kelsey, Haverford College
  - Jarett, Leonard and Donald Young, 1994; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
    William Pepper Laboratory
  - Jerry and Nancy, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Joe, 1942; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - John, Sabatio Susep, 1939; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Jones, Hunt B., 1986-1992; 4.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Kardon, Peter, 1990; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
    John Simon Guggenheim Foundation
  - Karsner, Howard, 1941; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
    Western Reserve University, Institute of Pathology
  - Karttunen, Frances E., 1987; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Kendall, Helen L., 1940; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
    Jeter, Hugh L.; University of Oklahoma
  - Kent, Roland G., 1934-1940; 7.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Kenward, Kevin, 1992; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
    American Medical Association
  - Kerr, Justin, 1995; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
    Postcard announcing lecture entitled "Where Do You Wear Your Paint Pot? A Discussion of Maya Scribes." The notation "John Nichols, Canada" appears on the card.
  - Kidder, Mary Helen, 1933; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Kingsbury, Isaac W., 1960; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Klar, Kathryn A., 1994; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Kolb, Alma Dean, 1978-1979; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
    International Journal of American Linguistics
  - Koontz, John E., 1986-1988; 11.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Krieger, Carlo J., 1987; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Lachner, Ernest A., 1963; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Lailer, Doris, 1995; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Landar, Herbert, 1966-1969; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Langendoen, D. Terence, 1987; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Larson, M. Burniece, 1939-1940; 10.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
    Medical Bureau
  - Lassiter, William L., 1934; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Laurent, Stephen, 1990; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Lee, Dorothy Sara, 1989; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
    Archives of Traditional Music, Indiana University
  - Lee, Penny, 1990-1995; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - LeFaivre-Rochester, Carol, 1996; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Leman, Wayne, 1984; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Lembke, Linda, 1990; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
    Green River Bindery
  - Lerch, Jimmy, 1948; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Lesser, Alexander, 1935; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
    American Ethnological Society
  - Letter Fragments, n.d.; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Linguistic Society of America, 1973; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Linton, Ralph, 1939; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
    American Anthropologist
  - Lips, Julius E., 1937; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
    Columbia University
  - Little, Elizabeth A., 1983-1985; 4.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Loewenstein, Benjamin, 1969; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Lolar, Louis, 1932-1934; 15.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Longley, G. T., 1934; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Loring, Laura and Gene, 1978; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Lounsbury, Floyd G., 1979; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Love, Timothy R., 1975-1986, n.d.; 9.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
    Penobscot Indian Community Action Program; Akin, Michael; Schweppe, Pamela
  - W. H. Lowdermilk and Company, 1929; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)